[{"question":"<p><strong>The joint of a skeleton that allows movement in only one plane is the <\/strong><\/p>","options":["ball and socket joint","gliding joint","vertebral joint","hinge joint"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Incomplete metamorphosis is found in these organisms except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dragon fly","house fly","locust","cockroach"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which one of these insects is to be found in flour mills<\/strong><\/p>","options":["trogoderma","tribolium","sitophilus","callosobruchus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The unit of heredity is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chromosome","gene","chromatid","uterus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The site of fertilization in humans is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ovary","fallopian tube","vagina","uterus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fish liver oil is rich in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Vitamin A and D","Vitamin A and E","Vitamin A and B","Vitamin A and K"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In animals, food is stored as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["glucose","fructose","glycogen","starch"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>June 5 each year is associated with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Aids day","Ozone day","World environment day","World population day"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Leishmania donovani causes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["kala-azar","elphantiasis","sleeping sickness","malaria"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which region of the human body does the adult filterial worm reside?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["muscle","nervous system","blood","lymph"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>An animal shows resemblance with its surroundings. This phenomenon is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mimicry","camouflage","ammensalism","photo-cooperation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which one is not an insect?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["tick","ant","beetle","locust"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Bowing of legs in children is due to the deficiency of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Vitamin D","Vitamin A","Vitamin B-complex","Vitamin K"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which one of the following organs does not produce anti hormone?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["spleen","bulbs","kidney","placenta"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Horizontal stems that grow below the ground often near the surface of the soil are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["rhizomes","bulbs","tubers","corms"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following parts of a cell is living?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cell wall","calciumloxalate","food vacuole","mitochondria"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Cells without an organized nucleus are called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["heterokaryote","eukaryote","prokaryote","synkaryote"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sites for energy transfer within a cell is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["golgi apparatus","paranchyma","mitochondria I","nuceolus"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Food and dissolved oxygen pass from the water directly into the amoeba by a process called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["transport","diffusion","fission","transpiration"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which one of these functions is not performed by the nervous system?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["receive sensory input from internal and external environment","digestion","integration","response to stimuli"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In man, gas exchange occurs in the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["heart","white blood cell","lung","kidney"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A plant cell is different from an animal cell because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the nucleus is pushed to the centre","the nucleus is small","the cell wall is made of cellulose","the cytoplasm fills up the entire cell space"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In transverse section of a dicot stem<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the xylem is more deeply located than the phloem","the cambium lies between the vascular bundles and the cortex","the epidermis is completely encircled by the cortex","the vascular bundles are randomly distributed within in cortex"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The spongy mesophyll is a tissue found in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["animal cells","plant leaves","plant roots","plant stem"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the nephron, reabsorption of water takes place in the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bowman's casule","Glomerulus","Renal tubules","Selective membranes"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mixture of a food substance and Benedict's solution was that there is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fatty acid","sucrose","amino acid","reducing sugar"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sperm cells are produced in the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["penis","bladder","testes","prostrate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Photosynthetic pigments are localized in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chloroplast","stroma","stomata","thylakoids"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a person lives exclusively on a diet of milk, eggs and bread, he is likely to suffer from&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["scurvy","rickets","beri-beri","night blindness"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The bryophytes are important parts of certain food chains because they<\/strong><\/p>","options":["grow in great masses","play a role in the natural aging of lakes and ponds","they choke up other life forms in the lakes","they resemble green algae"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In many plants, the growing tips elongate fastest and are said to be&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["meristematic","apically dorminant","phototropic","geotropic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Movement of water through a semi permeable membrane because the meritrane moves or expands thus overcoming the resistance of hydrostatic pressure is referred to as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["diffusion","osmosis","osmotic potential","turgor pressure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the following list of types of mutation, identify the one that is not hereditary<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Genetic mutation","Somatic mutation","Germinal mutation","Gametic mutation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these would not be a limiting factor in photosynthesis?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["O<sub>2<\/sub>","CO<sub>2<\/sub>","Chlorophyll","Light"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these would not be a limiting factor in photosynthesis?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["O<sub>2<\/sub>","CO<sub>2<\/sub>","Chlorophyll","Light"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a cell digestive system, enzymes mostly occur in the following except&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ribosome","lysosome","mitochondria","plastids"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these is not a lipid?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["wax","sterol","glycerol","lecithin"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Phototropism is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a unilateral response to light","a bilateral response to light","both unilateral and bilateral response to light","a hormonal gradient created within the organ"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>On storage, the sweetness of corn is lost. This is because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["polysaccharide is converted into soluble sugar","concentration of sugar increases due to storage","conversion of sugar to polysaccharide","enzymes responsible for the conversion are lost"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The site of protein synthesis in a cell is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["golgi apparatus","ribosomes","lysosomes","nucleus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The eye worm is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["wuchereiria banerofti","brugia malayi","loa loa","dracunenlus medinensis"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these plant is not a pitcher plant?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nepenthes","Crotalaria","Sarracema","Dionacea"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The highly developed cortex of the brain of man enables us to do the following except&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["think","reason out","memorize","maintain balance of the body"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lamp brush chrosome occurs in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["salivary gland","lymph gland","cancer cell","cocyte"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Insulin is secreted by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["gall bladder","pancreas","liver","spleen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The principal energy storing molecule is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NADP","FAD","ATP","ADP"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p>Each month the uterus lining thickens up in readiness to receive the fertilized egg. If the egg is not fertilized, the lining and some blood is lost through the vagina. This is called<\/p>","options":["ovulation","gestation","fertilization","menstration"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mitochondrion consist of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chemicals that break up complex compounds in the cells into simpler compounds","rich store of ribonucleic acid","digestive enzymes and hormones","protein, phosphorus and fats"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Amoeba, the ectoplasm is bounded by a thin membrane known as the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["plasmasol","plasmalge","plasmalemma","protoplsam"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Centipedes are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["equally dangerous than all","less dangerous than millipedes","more dangerous than all","not dangerous at all"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Wattle is the name of a structure found in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["lizard","cameleon","cock","dogfish"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these is not a feature of the caudal vertebrae in a mammal<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they possess neural canal","their transverse processes are poorly developed","their neural spines are gradually lost","there are not many article surfaces"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The inner ear has two types of coiled structures called cochlea which<\/strong><\/p>","options":["receive sound impulses","has sensory cells which carry impulses to the spinal cord","connects to the eustachaiar tube","possess cells sensitive to balance"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The viruses are the smallest known organisms and are divided into two parts the outer and an inner part. The outer part is protein and the inner parts ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["nucleus","vacuole","particle","DNA and RNA"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The thallus of a lichen consists of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a virus and fungal","algal cells and fungal hypae","bacteria and fungal cells","soredium and basisiospor"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The palisade parenchyma is found in the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["stem","leaf","flower","root"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Crenation occurs in the red blood cell when<\/strong><\/p>","options":["it is placed in isotonic solution","it is placed in hypertonic solution","osmosis is allowed to occur","transpiration occurs"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The capillaries act as filers between<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the veins","the arteries","the venules","the arteries and the veins"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The primary opening for gaseous exchange in a plant stem at night are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["opening in the cuticles","stomata","lenticels","branches"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The outer membrane covering the brain is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["brain ventricle","anechoic","piamater","dura mater"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"}]